NB

NATALIE BOALER



215 Dawlish Road, Leyton, London, E10 6QN.



+447841749682



natalieboaler@gmail.com



https://www.wastenotwant that.co/



https://www.linkedin.com/in/natalieboaler/



https://www.instagram.com/ceramicsbytilly/?hl=en

ABOUT ME

Passionate, innovative & highly motivated, trend lead fashion designer with a strong commercial eye & over 15 years experience of working in the industry. Focused in designing multi-product ranges for the branded market, across Men's, Women's & Childrenswear.

SKILLS

- 15 years of experience in the design industry has given excellent team working & time management skills furthermore enabling to work well under pressure.
- Great communication skills working with factories and within a design team.
- A passion & knowledge of sustainability, projected through my Instagram & blog Waste Not Want That, https://www.wastenotwantthat.co/.
- Excellent computer literacy: Highly experienced using Adobe Illustrator, Photoshop, InDesign, Microsoft Word, Excel and PowerPoint.

EXPERIENCE

Freelance Designer

February 2022 - To date. Current clients are WGSN, ASOS, Belstaff & UCLA.

Jack Wills, Senior Womenswear Designer

April 2019 - February 2022.

- Researching & creating the direction, colour palette & looks for each season of the Womenswear collection.
- Designing high quality, fashion forward multi-product with a focus on jersey, sweat, activewear, loungewear & graphics.
- Sourcing & developing new fabrics with a focus on sustainability.
- Working closely with factories to produce high quality garments in the correct fit, whilst following the critical path.

Brand Machine Group, Senior Childrenswear Designer

April 2018 - April 2019.

- The sole designer for girls & teenwear Juicy Couture brands Juicy by Juicy & Juicy Black. Working on all product groups including wovens, soft wovens, jersey, outerwear, activewear, swimwear, accessories and loungewear.
- Designer for Franklin & Marshall boyswear, designing all product categories.
- Constantly researching both the womens & menswear market & translating it into children & teen trends.
- Creating the looks, colour palette & direction for all three fashion focused brands.

Lindbergh, Senior Menswear Designer (Denmark)

July 2017 - April 2018.

- Designing outerwear, shirts, bottoms, denim, knits, sweat, jersey, accessories, sportswear & graphics for all product groups.
- Focusing on design details & fabric functions to get the best from each product.
- Sourcing & developing new fabrics for each season.
- Researching & creating the look, trends & colour palettes for each season.

Jack & Jones, Bestseller, Senior Menswear Designer (Denmark) October 2014 – July 2017.

• Working on Originals & Core main range, designing tee & sweat collections alongside creating the main look & colour palette for the season.



NATALIE BOALER



215 Dawlish Road, Leyton, London, E10 6QN.



+447841749682



natalieboaler@gmail.com



https://www.wastenotwant that.co/



https://www.linkedin.com/in/ natalieboaler/



https://www.instagram.com/ceramicsbytilly/?hl=en

- Managing & briefing the graphics team to ensure a strong & varied graphic collection whilst being suitable for all countries.
- Ensuring the collection has a strong Jeanswear foundation whilst covering the latest fashion trends.
- Reacting on sales feedback, pushing fabric & print development to create a price focused, new & innovative collection covering all countries needs.

River Island, Menswear Jersey & Sweat Designer

August 2012 - September 2014.

- Working in a very fast paced environment, focusing on 3 seasons alongside each other, keeping to tight deadlines whilst designing new & considered product.
- Briefing suppliers & in house graphic designers to develop t-shirt prints to fit into part of the range.
- Working as part of a team alongside Buyers to range build a commercial yet fashion forward collection, catering for our three main customer target audiences.
- Working with & visiting factories based in India, Turkey & Mauritius to ensure the product is developed to the highest standard.
- Constant & in depth trend research & prediction to enable an innovative collection.

UCLA, Senior Men's & Womenswear Designer

August 2008 - August 2012.

- Progressed from designer to senior within one & a half years whilst growing with the brand, dramatically increasing sales figures each season & continually inputting new systems to create a smooth running & efficient design team.
- In-depth market & trend research across Men's & Women's multi product, including regular research trips around the UK, abroad, trade & fabric shows.
- Managing & motivating a 4 man design team to ensure designs are created to the highest standard whilst meeting all deadlines, ensuring the team communicates & works well together.
- Designed across all product areas such as graphics, jerseys, wovens, knitwear & accessories whilst keeping to price points & the UCLA brand identity.
- Liaised with factories to ensure all deadlines & critical paths are met whilst ensuring tech packs are followed correctly & the product is made to the highest standard, this also involves regular factory visits to India & China.

Cohen & Wilks Ltd, Childrenswear Design & Merchandiser

July 2006 – September 2007 (year in industry).

River Island, Sales Assistant

February 2005 - June 2006.

EDUCATION

2004-2008 The University of Leeds.

BA (Hons) Fashion Design (Ind): 2:1.

2002-2003 Garibaldi Sixth Form College, Mansfield.

A Level: Photography (B), English (C), Art (C).

AS Level Psychology (B).

2001-2002 Garibaldi Comprehensive School, Mansfield.

10 GCSE's (A-C) including English (A), Maths (B), Science (B).